chariot.net.au 2006-06-18

# Chariot Limited Privacy Policy

**CHARIOT LIMITED  
PRIVACY POLICY STATEMENT**

* * *

At Chariot, we are committed to the protection of your personal information. Chariot's business is governed by the _Telecommunications Act of 1997_ , _Industry Codes of Practice_ and Chariot's own policies and procedures. This includes Chariot Internet Limited - Privacy Policy Statement, which have been designed to ensure that your personal information is protected. 

Our Privacy Statement contains important information regarding your use of Chariot�s services. When you visit our web sites, you should read the information provided as it will affect your use of our services. 

Our Privacy Policy may be subject to change from time to time so we strongly encourage you to check our online Privacy Policy Statement regularly. 

**What we mean by Personal / Sensitive Information**

When we refer to your personal information we mean information or an opinion including those that form part of our data base that can be used to identify you. While sensitive information refers to details of your race or ethnicity, religious or beliefs or affiliations, membership of a professional or trade association or union, sexual preferences or practices, criminal record or health information. 

**Who controls your Personal Information**

Any personal information provided or to be gathered by us is controlled primarily by Chariot Internet Limited (ABN 31 088 377 860) of 214 Greenhill Road Eastwood 5063 in the State of South Australia as well as Chariot�s many trading branches nationally. 

**What Information do we collect and how do we use it**

When you apply for our service we need to know your:

  * name;
  * address;
  * contact numbers;
  * date of birth; and
  * drivers licence number.

In addition, we may require other information from/about you including but not limited to: country of origin and gender. 

If you elect to pay for our services via credit cards we need to know your card details such as:

  * type of card;
  * card number;
  * credit card verification number ("cvn");
  * expiry dates; and
  * name of card-holder.

Some of the information we require from you is mandatory by law as well as for our purposes. That is, it enables us to set up and administer your account, properly profile/identify you, ensure your account is secured and generally enables you to get the most out of our services. 

We also use the information we collect for purposes other than those specified above if:

  1. you would reasonably expect us to use the personal information for that other purpose, and
  2. that other purpose is related to the purposes specified above, for example, to enable us to occasionally contact you about:
    * essential information about our services and your account;
    * important changes to our services and how it will affect your account.

We may also use your personal information for the purpose of direct marketing, for example to let you know of:
  * new services we offer;
  * special offers we think you may find valuable.

We may only do this where it is impracticable to obtain your prior express consent. You may notify us when we first contact you that you do not wish to receive any further marketing communications from us. You will have this option in our communication to you. 

You may also notify us at any time that you do not wish to receive any marketing communications from us by contacting us - [click here to send us your request](mailto:privacy@chariot.net.au). We will respect your wishes. 

If we wish to use any of your personal information for any other purpose other than those specified above, we will not do so unless we have your express consent to do so. 

However, there are specific circumstances where we are allowed to, for example:

  * where there are reasonable grounds to believe that disclosure is necessary to prevent a threat to life or health;
  * where Chariot suspects that unlawful activity is or has been engaged in and uses the personal information, information or data to investigate the suspected unlawful activity; or
  * the use is authorised by law or reasonably necessary to enforce the law. These uses may include where Chariot is required to provide information in response to subpoenas or warrants or other legal processes including requests from the Australian Stock Exchange and other Statutory bodies.

Please note that for our business purpose as well as in compliance with record-keeping obligations under Commonwealth and State laws we keep logs of your usage (including but not limited to the telephone number you dialled in from and the number you used to access our service) as well as make copies of or store records including personal information. 

In all cases, your information will be held in strict confidence. 

We will not collect any sensitive information from you unless in certain circumstances, for example:

  * where you have given express consent to Chariot to do so;
  * where there are reasonable grounds to believe that disclosure is necessary to prevent a threat to life or health;
  * the use is authorised by law or reasonably necessary to enforce the law; or
  * when the information is necessary for the establishment, exercise or defence of a legal claim.

**Information collected from visits to our Web Site**

When you visit our site to read or download information, we record the following for our own troubleshooting, security, marketing and statistical purposes:

  * Your IP address;
  * The date and time you accessed our site;
  * The previous page you visited before visiting our site (�referrer�);
  * The pages you have accessed and the documents downloaded;
  * The version and type of browser you use;
  * The success/failure code; and
  * Your Operating System.

We use web server programs (Analogs and Webtrends) to collect the above information. The information we collected is used to create summary statistics which allows us to assess the number of visitors to the different sections of our site, discover what information is most and least used, determine technical design specifications, and help us make our site more useful to visitors. 

No attempt will be made to identify users or their browsing activities except, in the unlikely event of an investigation, where a law enforcement agency may exercise a warrant to inspect our logs. 

**Information collected from visits to other Web Sites hosted by our servers**

Our web site contains links to other sites. Chariot is not responsible for the content and the privacy practices of other web sites and encourages you to examine each site's privacy policies and make your own decisions regarding the reliability and correctness of material and information found. 

Please be aware that when you visit websites owned by third parties who have their sites hosted with our servers, the information that are collected using Analogs and Webtrends is used by these third parties for their own purposes, which we have no control over, and do not take any responsibility for their actions. 

**Cookies**

Cookies are data stored on an individual�s computer hard drive for record keeping. Cookie identifies and recognises the computer (but not the person using the computer). The use of cookies is an industry standard and you will find most major websites use them. We do not use cookies, however by using our service, you may be subject to cookies being used by other web site owners/operators. We do not have access to or control over these cookies or any information they may collect from you. Most Internet browsers are pre-set to accept cookies. If you prefer not to receive cookies, you can adjust your Internet browser to disable cookies or to warn you when cookies are being used. 

**Disclosure of your Personal Information**

We respect your privacy and take it seriously. As such, the information we collect from you is strictly confidential. We will not reveal, disclose, sell, distribute, rent, licence, share or pass that information on to any third parties, other than those who are contracted to Chariot to keep the information confidential or are subject to a statute or binding scheme which imposes similar restrictions to Chariot Internet Limited - Privacy Policy Statement regarding the management and handling of personal information, and that we are satisfied that there are adequate systems in place to ensure that the data collected is stored in a secure environment. For example, we may disclose your personal and or sensitive information to third parties for the establishment, exercise or defence of a legal claim. When you apply for Domain Name registration through us we need to disclose the information you provide us to the relevant Domain Name registration companies. 

We may disclose the personal information, other information or data we collect from you for the purpose specified to you at the time of collection or for another purpose if:

  * you would reasonably expect us to disclose it for that purpose; and
  * that purpose is related to the purpose specified to you at the time of collection.

If we wish to disclose any of this personal information, information or data other than as set out above, we will not do so unless we have your express consent to do so. 

We will not provide your personal information to third parties without your consent, except:

  * where there are reasonable grounds to believe that disclosure is necessary to prevent a threat to life or health;
  * where Chariot suspects that unlawful activity is or has been engaged in and uses the personal information, information or data to investigate the suspected unlawful activity; or,
  * the use is authorised by law or reasonably necessary to enforce the law. These uses may include where Chariot is required to provide information in response to subpoenas or warrants or other legal process including requests from the Australian Stock Exchange.

**Security of your Personal Information**

We will take reasonable precautions to ensure that all information we collect, use or disclose is accurate, complete, up-to-date and stored in a secure environment and accessed only by authorised persons. 

It is important to bear in mind that, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be absolutely secure. While we endeavour to protect your personal information from misuse and loss and unauthorised access, modification or disclosure, we cannot guarantee the security of any information you transmit to us or receive from our online products or services. These activities are conducted at your own risk. Once we receive your transmission, we make our best effort to ensure its security. 

Please note, we will not be responsible for any unauthorised access or use of information held by us. We will also not be responsible if your information is accessed through an unauthorised or improper use of your account or membership privileges due to your failure to adequately secure your password. 

When you apply for an account with us you will create a user name and password. You can play an important role in keeping your personal information secure, by maintaining the confidentiality of any password and accounts used on the Website. If you suspect that someone has your user name and password and you do not want them to have it, please let us know or change them immediately. You can update your password, including providing us with specific request on what actions to be taken in relation to your account and personal information. We will endeavour to act on your instructions if we believe your request is reasonable and is in within our capability. 

Our employees and contractors will have access to your personal information to a level that is necessary to enable them to perform their jobs. They are obliged to respect the confidentiality of any personal information held by us. 

Credit card information is among the most sensitive and important data that we collect. Chariot operates secure servers to minimise the risk of unauthorised use of such information. Credit card information that is transmitted via our secure servers is encrypted in accordance with the highest standards. For obvious reasons, please do not send credit card information through unsecured electronic mail. 

**You can access, correct or update your information**

You will always have access to the information and content that you provide to us. There are exceptions to this right and they include:

  * where providing access will pose a serious threat to life or health of any individual or pose an unreasonable impact on the privacy of an individual;
  * your request for access is frivolous or vexatious;
  * where the information relates to existing legal proceedings between Chariot and you and the information would not be discoverable in the process of those legal proceedings; or
  * where providing access would be unlawful, may prejudice an investigation of possible unlawful activity, may prejudice enforcement of laws, or denying access is specifically authorised by law.

If we do not allow you access to your personal information, we will endeavour to provide you with the reasons for our decision. 

You can choose to modify or delete your personal information, unless it is mandatory information required for your membership application. If you believe that the personal information we collected about you is inaccurate, incomplete, or not up-to-date please [notify us immediately](mailto:privacy@chariot.net.au) so that we may correct and/or update the information. 

**Minors**

It is our policy that minors (persons under 18 years of age) must have their guardian�s consent/guidance before using our service. Any account minors may have with us will be in the guardian�s name. Whilst we will make every reasonable effort to ensure that children's privacy and other rights are not compromised, it is ultimately the responsibility of guardians to monitor their children's Internet usage. 

**Notification of changes to the Privacy Policy**

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on our Website so you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. If at any point we decide to use Personally Identifiable Information in a manner different from that stated at the time it was collected, we will notify you by way of an email. You will have a choice as to whether or not we use your information in this different manner. We will use information in accordance with the privacy policy under which the information was collected. 

**In Summary**

At Chariot, we are committed to protecting your privacy. You as an individual are responsible for the security of and access to your own computer. It is ultimately your responsibility to ensure that you maintaining the secrecy of your username and passwords and any account information. For your security and for the benefit of others, please be careful and responsible whenever you are using the Internet. 

Please also be aware that whenever you voluntarily disclose personal information over the Internet (for example: in discussion forums, via email, or in chat sites) this information can be collected and used by others. If you post personal information in publicly accessible online forums, you may receive unsolicited messages from other parties in return. 

**Additional Privacy Information**

If you are interested in obtaining additional information of privacy, you can visit the Australian Federal Privacy Commissioner's website at [http://www.privacy.gov.au](http://www.privacy.gov.au/).
